Juan Manuel Kelsy Romero

https://www.linkedin.com/in/juan-manuel-kelsy-romero-226485136/ +57 3014522814 jkelsy@gmail.com

Career Summary

Developer with 15+ years of experience in the design and development of applications under business architecture, experience in analysis and design of new systems, knowledge of software architectures and application integration, cloud development capabilities, leadership skills, good interpersonal relationships and learning capacity.

Summary of Qualifications

Skills:

AWS Angular CouchBase Groovy Spring Quarkus Python PHP SQL Kafka Grails Flask Kotlin Java Docker Django HTML + CSS

Career History

Globant, Medellín, Colombia

Tech Lead / Java Software Engineer Software Designer May. 2022 – Current

- Technical Leader for the backend team in the Unified Experience Portal Project (AirMiles).
- Development Backend MicroServices with Spring Boot and Java 17.
- Working with CI/CD using Jenkins and AWS (Cloud Formation, Fargate, RDS, S3, API Gateway)
 Docker (Deploying containerized microservices)
- Working with agile methodology: SCRUM.
- Construction and define US according to the client requirements.
- Development Unit and integration tests, and using quality code tools like Sonar, or Prisma Cloud vulnerability tool.
- Using Jira.

Overactive(Perficient), Remote, Colombia

Software Java Engineer Software Designer May. 2021 – May 2022

- Backend development in Evertec Project (Puerto Rico Popular Bank).
- Development Backend Services with Spring Boot and Java 11.
- Development Infrastructure as code with CDK and TypeScript.
- Development AWS Lambdas with Python.
- Development performance tests with JMeter.
- Development in house Jenkins's pipeline with Groovy.

Globant, Medellín, Colombia

Technical Leader / Software Engineer Senior Java Developer

- Technical Leader for the Backend Team in Prisma (TodoPago Argentina).
- Developed e-commerce's core system using microservices with Spring Boot and Kotlin.
- Using Spring Cloud.
- Using Kafka, Redis, Docker.
- Defining technical notes to the US according to the business team.
- Working with agile methodology: SCRUM.
- AWS(S3, RDS, EKS)
- Using Jira.
- Backend development of the core system for Turmetrics project for United Airlines.
- Development Integration Services with Spring Boot.
- Using Spring Integration.
- Using Kafka, Tibco EMS, CouchBase.
- Working with agile methodology: SCRUM.
- Using TFS.

Intergrupo, Medellín, Colombia

Senior Java Developer

Oct. 2018 - Oct. 2019

May. 2018 - Oct. 2018

- Backend development of the core system that will handle transfers made by clients in a multi channel environment.
- Development of Rest Services with Spring Boot.
- Making Stored Procedure with PL/SQL for Oracle.
- Using Spring Data for ORM.
- Working with agile methodology: SCRUM.
- Using Azure DevOps.

Pragma, Medellín, Colombia

Senior Java Developer

Developed Portlets for IBM WebSphere Portal.

- Managed Persistence with JPA to connect Oracle database.
- Support for the system in production.
- Made reports with JasperReports.

Universidad de Córdoba, Montería, Colombia

Freelance Developer

Development of a digital certificate generation and signing system, integrated with a payment platform using Python and Diango.

Comfacor, Montería, Colombia

FullStack Software Developer

- Created the intranet of the company.
- Developed the Online Enrollment System (Python Flask).
- Developed the Document management system of the Company.
- Created the intranet using PHP (CakePHP), Mysql.

Oct. 2019 – May 2021

Jun. 2010 – Mar. 2017

Mar. 2017 - May. 2018

- Developed web applications using Groovy (Grails).
- Developed web applications using JavaEE.
- Deployed the applications using Wildfly and Tomcat.
- Integrated Solr for indexing documents.
- Integrated the web application with MS SQL Server.
- Integrated JasperReports Server with the applications.
- Made reports with JasperReports.

Universidad de Córdoba, Montería, Colombia Professor

Jan. 2006 - Dec. 2014

Teached classes of programming languages such Object Pascal, Java or PHP, and classes of web programming.

Corporación Universitaria San Martín, Montería, Colombia

Jan. 2005 – Dec. 2008

Professor

Teached classes of programming languages such Object Pascal, Java or PHP, and classes of web programming.

Universidad de Córdoba, Montería, Colombia

Jan. 2004 – Dec. 2008

Software Developer

- Created a Virtual Learning Environment.
- Developed the Backend application with PHP and Mysql.
- Developed the Frontend with HTML, JQuery and CSS.
- Lead development team.

Education

Universidad de Córdoba, Montería, Colombia Degree in computer science and audiovisual media. Jun. 1996 – Dec. 2003

Universidad de Santander, Bucaramanga, Colombia Administration of educational informatics.

May. 2011 – Oct. 2012